A Guide to the Virginia Educational Media Association Records, 1952-2011 (ongoing)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Educational Media Association Records, 1952-2011 (ongoing)
The Library of Virginia
35673
13.5 cubic feet (34 boxes and 2 oversize folders)
Virginia Educational Media Association
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Virginia Educational Media Association, in various accessions:
Accession 35673, received 14 January 1998
Accession 36167, received 28 October 1998
Accession 37093, received 19 November 1999
Accession 38037, received 11 April 2001
Accession 40363, received 10 January 2003
Accession 43479, received 10 October 2007
Accession 44424, received 5 November 2008 and 6 August 2009
Accession 50225, received 18 November 2011
Biographical Information
The Virginia Educational Media Association (VEMA) was formed in 1975 when the Virginia Association for Educational Communications and Technology (VAECT) and the Virginia Education Association--School Librarian Department (VEA-SLD) merged. VEMA's mission is to be the recognized voice for excellence in Virginia's school libraries. Its aim is to promote literacy, information access and evaluation, love of literature, effective use of technology, collaboration in the teaching/learning process, intellectual freedom, professional growth, instructional leadership, and lifelong learning.
Scope and Content
Records, 1952-2002, of the Virginia Educational Media Association (VEMA) consisting of its organizational files, board meeting minutes, president's papers, financial records, annual conference files, education files, subject files, directories, published materials, and miscellaneous files. Organizational files include joint study by VAECT and VEA-SLD for merger, constitution, motion books, and policies and procedures handbooks. Board meeting files consist of executive board minutes, board minutes, annual conference minutes, reports, budgets, correspondence, position papers, scholarships and awards, election results, agenda, membership lists, goals, and other related papers. President's papers files include AASL affiliation application, awards and scholarships, budgets, reports, correspondence, committees, VEMA and Virginia Library Association joint conference papers, and minutes. Financial records consist of cash receipts and payments records, check stubs and cancelled checks, bank statements and records, accounting records, and treasurer's financial reports. Annual conference files include the minutes of the annual meetings, programs, and award announcements. Education files consist of annual reports and bank statements for scholarships and awards, Dickinson Scholarship applications, Student Media Festival, School Library Media Day and Month, leadership conference files, and regional conference files. Subject files include board lists, position papers, certification studies, studies, MEMO records, minutes, photographs and newspaper clippings, membership forms and brochures, Governor's Conference on Library and Information Services, Southern Regional Media Leadership Council, and AECT membership files. Directories list both the VEMA board and general membership.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Organizational Files
Series II. Board Meeting Files
Series III. President's Papers Files
Series IV. Financial Records
Series V. Annual Conference Files
Series VI. Education Files
Series VII. Subject Files
Series VIII. Directories
Series IX. Published Materials
Series X. Photographs
Series XI. Miscellaneous Files
Series XII. 1998 Addition (Accession 36167)
Series XIII. 2003 Addition (Accession 40363)
Series XIV. 2007 Addition (Accession 43479)
Series XV. 2009 Addition (Accession 44424)
Series XVI. 2011 Addition (Accession 50225)
Contents List
- Series I. Organizational Files, 1973-1999.
  - Virginia Association for Educational Communications and Technology (VAECT)/Virginia Education Association, School Librarian Department (VEA-SLD) Joint Study, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - VEMA Constitution, 1975; proposed changes, 1979; Constitution for Virginia Association for Educational Communications and Technology, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - VEMA's Vision 2000, 1998-1999; VEMA strategic plan (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Motions book, 1976-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Motions with cross references, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Motions with cross references, secretary's copy, 1976-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Policy and Procedure Manual, working draft, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Policies and Procedures Handbook, 1993 (Acc. 35673) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Policies and Procedures Handbook, 1993 (Acc. 37093) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Policies and Procedures Handbook, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series II. Board Meeting Files, 1968-1999.
  - VEA-VAECT minutes, 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, annual business meeting minutes, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Annual business meeting minutes, Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Budget, election results.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, annual business meeting minutes, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Board meeting minutes, annual membership meeting minutes (reports), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Reports.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, board meeting minutes, annual membership meeting minutes, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Board meeting minutes, annual membership meeting minutes, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Board meeting minutes, annual business meeting minutes, 1983-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Board meeting minutes, 20 June 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Board meeting minutes, annual conference business meeting minutes, Mediagram (Fall 1987), 15-17 October 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Board meeting minutes, 4 December 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Correspondence, reports, agenda, membership list, job description.
  - Board meeting minutes, 30 January 1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Reports, conference announcements, scholarships and awards offered.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 19 February 1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Conferences, position paper, AASL, luncheon, awards and scholarships.
  - Board meeting minutes, 9 May 1988 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    VEMA ballot, correspondence, Mediagram.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, board meeting minutes, 4-5 November 1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Reports, new members list, correspondence, conference, goals, clipping, media festival rules and regulations, budget, AASL, awards, Mediagram.
  - Board meeting minutes, 10 December 1988 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Reports, conferences, budget.
  - Board meeting minutes, 25 February 1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Reports, Media Month, memberships.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 6 May 1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Reports, conferences.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, board meeting minutes, 8 July 1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Budget, correspondence, reports, conferences, scholarships and awards.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 25 October 1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Budget, reports, conferences.
  - Board meeting minutes, 26 October 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Reports, conferences, scholarships and awards.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, board meeting minutes, 1-2 December 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Reports, correspondence, conferences.
  - Board meeting minutes, 1990-1997 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Reports, resolutions, position papers, testimony.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 2 March 1990. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Board meeting minutes, 3 March 1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Reports, correspondence, conferences, Media Festivals.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 21 June 1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Reports, budget.
  - Board meeting minutes, 22 June 1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Reports, conferences, correspondence.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, board meeting minutes, annual business meeting minutes, 14-17 November 1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 18 January 1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Board meeting minutes, 19 January 1991 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 15 March 1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Board meeting minutes, 16 March 1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Correspondence, reports, conferences, bank statements.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 27 June 1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Reports, budget, correspondence.
  - Board meeting minutes, 28 June 1991 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Reports, budget, correspondence, conferences.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 31 October 1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Reports, goals.
  - Board meeting minutes, 31 October 1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Reports, correspondence, goals, legislature election booklets.
  - Annual business meeting minutes, 1 November 1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Board meeting minutes, 2 November 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Conferences, goals.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 6 December 1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Board meeting minutes, 6 December 1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Reports, position paper, budget, conferences, correspondence, AASL.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 28 February 1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Reports, AASL, correspondence.
  - Board meeting minutes, 29 February 1992 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Reports, correspondence, conferences, AASL, AETC, scholarships and awards.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 18 June 1992 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Reports, correspondence, conference, budget.
  - Board meeting minutes, 19 June 1992 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Reports, correspondence.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 4 November 1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Reports, Prince William Association of School Librarians.
  - Board meeting minutes, 5 November 1992 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 5 February 1993 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Reports, 1992 conference evaluations, Virginia Department of Education).
  - Business meeting minutes, 6 February 1993 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Reports, conferences, AASL, Student Media Festival.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 7 May 1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Board meeting minutes, 8 May 1993 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Reports, resolutions, conferences.
  - Executive Board meeting agenda, board meeting minutes, 18-19 June 1993 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Reports, budget, position statement, address, correspondence, assessments.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, board meeting minutes, annual business meeting minutes, 20-21 October 1993 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Budget, reports, Society of Government Meeting Planners.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 4 March 1994 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Conference location information.
  - Board meeting minutes, 5 March 1994 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Reports, Virginia Library Legislative Day, AASL resolutions, correspondence, Virginia Library Information Network.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 13 May 1994 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Board meeting minutes, 14 May 1994 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Reports, conference, Media Festival.
  - Board meeting minutes, 24-25 September 1994 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Reports, conference, Virginia Library Information Network.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 19 October 1994 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Board meeting minutes, 20 October 1994 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Reports, questionnaires.
  - Board meeting minutes, 7 January 1995 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Report, proposal, job description, book synopsis.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 12 May 1995 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Board meeting minutes, 13 May 1995 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Reports, correspondence, proposals.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 15 August 1995 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Correspondence.
  - Board meeting minutes, 16 August 1995 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Informational pamphlet layout.
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 18 October 1995 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Annual business meeting minutes, 19-20 October 1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Reports, budget, questionnaires, Media Festival, conference evaluation forms.
  - Board meeting minutes, 27 January 1996 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Reports, web page, strategic plan.
  - Board meeting minutes, 27 April 1996 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Reports, conference planning, correspondence.
  - VEMA regional directors' meeting minutes, 11 August 1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Conferences.
  - Board meeting minutes, 21 September 1996 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Budget, reports, strategic plans, conferences.
  - Board meeting minutes, 24 October 1996 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Board meeting minutes, January 1997 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Strategic plan, reports, conference evaluations, contracts.
  - Executive Board notes, 21 March 1997 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Board meeting minutes, 19 April 1997 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Reports, strategic plans, conferences.
  - Board meeting minutes, 20 September 1997 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Board meeting minutes, 15 October 1998 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Agenda, reports, contract agreements.
  - Board meeting minutes, 23 January 1999 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Agenda, Board directory, reports, correspondence, vendor registration and list.
  - Board meeting minutes, 24 April 1999 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Agenda, vendor registration, insurance, news releases, correspondence, reports.
  - Executive Board retreat minutes, 7-8 May 1999 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Agenda.
  - Board meeting minutes, 24 September 1999 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Agenda, Board directory, reports, constitution, by-laws, proposals.
- Series III. President's Papers, 1975-1993.
  - President's papers, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Affiliation application with American Association of School Librarians (AASL).
  - Awards and scholarships, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Board names and addresses, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Budget information, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Committees, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Incorporation, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, agenda, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Printing company, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Regional groups, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, reports, joint conference planning, position statements, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - VEMA-VLA joint conference, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 7-27)
  - Correspondence, agenda, reports, papers, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Reports, minutes, correspondence, memoranda, conferences, agenda, resumes, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, reports, budgets, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, programs, reports, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, agenda, minutes, reports, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, minutes, reports, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Reports, State Library newsletters, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Series IV. Financial Records, 1970-1987.
  - VEA-SLD and VEMA cash receipts and cash payments book, 1970-1976 (Box 7, Folder N/A)
  - Check stubs, cancelled checks, deposit slips and receipts, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Check stubs, cancelled checks, deposit slips and receipts, 1970-1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Check stubs, cancelled checks, 1972-1974 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Check stubs, cancelled checks, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Cash receipts and disbursement records, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Bank statements, balance comparisons, deposit slips, 1975-1978 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Accounting pages, 1976-1978 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Treasurer--financial reports, 1978-1983, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Series V. Annual Conference Files, 1975-2000.
  - Annual (inaugural) conference, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Annual conference, 1976-1990 (Box 8, Folder 5-20)
  - Annual conference, 1991-1997 (Box 9, Folder 1-7)
  - Annual conference, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 8-9)
  - Annual conference, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Annual conference, space schedule, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Series VI. Education Files, 1952-2001.
  - Scholarships and awards, 1956-1981 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Annual reports, bank statements, bank pass book.
  - Dickinson Scholarship and Margaret Rutherford Memorial, 1952-1970 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Dickinson Scholarship applications, 1954-1962 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Dickinson Scholarship applications, 1963-1968 (Box 10, Folder 4-7)
  - Dickinson Scholarship--Linda Sue Harrison--Winner, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Dickinson Scholarship--Phyllis Draper--Winner, 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Dickinson Scholarship--Sandra Cochran--Applicant, 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Dickinson Scholarship--June Courtney--Applicant, 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Dickinson Scholarship--Frances Lee Grandstaff--Winner, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Dickinson Scholarship--Bessie E. Jordan--Applicant, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Dickinson Scholarship--Julianna Gail Chilson--Winner, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Dickinson Scholarship--Deborah Kay Campbell--Applicant, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Dickinson Scholarship--Donna Joyce Huff--Winner, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Dickinson Scholarship--Susan Beth Halman--Winner, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Dickinson Scholarship--Patricia H. Davidson--Alternate, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Dickinson Scholarship applications, 1974-1978 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Student Media Festivals, 1978-2000 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - School Library Media Day, 1986, School Library Media Month, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - School Library Media Month, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
  - VEACT Spring Conference, 30-31 March 1973 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - VEMA/VLA Joint Conference, 17-19 November 1977 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - VEMA/VLA Joint Conference, 15-17 October 1998 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Southeastern Regional Media Leadership Conference, 8-11 March 1981 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Leadership Conference, 1975-1989 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Leadership Conference, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Leadership Conference, 1990-1995 (Box 11, Folder 11-16)
  - Leadership Conference, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Regional Conferences, 1979-1993 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Regional Conferences, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Regional Conferences - James Region, 1977-2001 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Series VII. Subject Files, 1969-1998.
  - VEMA Board list, VEMA budget, Virginia Board of Education members, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - VEMA Ad Hoc Committee on Position Papers, December 1989-March 1990 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Certification studies for media personnel, 1969-1973, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Library school in Virginia study, 1969-1979 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Managers of Media Organization (MEMO, a VEMA affiliate), 1980-1989 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Papers, minutes of Past-President Dr. Nancy Vick, 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - VEMA Connections, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Questionnaire, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Membership forms and other brochures (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Pamphlets (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Governor's Conference on Library and Information Services, 1979-1990 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Southern Regional Media Leadership Council, 1977-1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Association for Educational Communications and Technology (AECT, a VEMA affiliate), 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Deborah Cooke file (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - AECT membership certificates, 1974-1979 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Series VIII. Directories, 1977-2000.
  - VEMA Board Members and Committee Chairpersons Directory, 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - VEMA Board Members and Committee Chairpersons Directory, 1988-1989 (revised 12/88) (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - VEMA Board Members and Committee Chairpersons Directory, 1988-1989 (revised 7/89) (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - VEMA Board Members and Chairpersons Directory, 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - VEMA Board Members and Committee Chairpersons Directory, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - VEMA Officers, Regional Directors, Committee Chairpersons, and Non-Voting Departments Directory, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - VEMA officers and board directory, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Board Directory, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Board Directory, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - VEMA Officers Rosters, 1994-1995 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - VEMA membership list, 1977-1978 (Accession 35673) (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - VEMA membership list, 1977-1978 (Accession 37093) (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - VEMA membership roster, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - New members (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - VEMA membership directories, 1978-2000 (Box 14, Folder N/A)
  - Speaker/presenter directory (Box 14, Folder N/A)
  - VEMA Learning Disabilities Directory, 1999-2000 (Box 14, Folder N/A)
  - Address mailing label list (Box 14, Folder N/A)
- Series IX. Published Materials, 1976-2000.
  - Criteria for Technical Education: A Suggested Guide (Box 15, Folder N/A)
  - A Guide to Virginia's Literary Heritage (Box 15, Folder N/A)
  - High Tech and Teacher Training: A Book of Readings (Box 15, Folder N/A)
  - International Instructional Media...A Book of Readings (Box 15, Folder N/A)
  - Media Selection Aids: A Bibliography (Box 15, Folder N/A)
  - Resource Guide to Intellectual Freedom (Accessions 35673, 37093) (Box 15, Folder N/A)
  - Standards for School Media Programs (Box 15, Folder N/A)
  - Tapestry of Appalachian People and Places (Accessions 35673, 38037) (Box 15, Folder N/A)
  - Virginia Educational Media Association Calendar, 1991 (Box 15, Folder N/A)
  - Mediagrams, 1976-1995 (Box 16, Folder N/A)
  - Mediagrams, 1996-2000 (Box 17, Folder N/A)
  - VEMA Journal, 1986-1991 (Box 17, Folder N/A)
  - VSTE Journal, Winter 2000 (Box 17, Folder N/A)
- Series X. Photographs and newspaper clippings, 1946, 1970s-1998
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - University of Virginia newsletter, 1 November 1946 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, VEMA representatives with Governor Mills Godwin, 24 April 1976 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 1970s (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, VEMA annual conferences, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, annual conference, Roanoke, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, annual conference, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, regional conferences (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, Mediagram (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Series XI. Miscellaneous Files,1975-1981, undated.
  - Audio cassette tapes of programs from various conferences (Box 19, Folder N/A)
  - Pens (Box 19, Folder N/A)
  - Pouches (Box 19, Folder N/A)
  - Rulers (Box 19, Folder N/A)
  - Slides from James Region Conference, 1981 (Box 19, Folder N/A)
  - VEMA bumper sticks (Box 19, Folder N/A)
  - VEMA pin (Box 19, Folder N/A)
  - VEMA buttons (Box 19, Folder N/A)
  - Mock-ups for program cover and membership certificate, 1975 (1 oversize folder) (Box 65, Folder 0005627307)
- Series XII. 1998 Addition (Accession 36167), 1976-1978, 1995-1998.
  - Board meeting, September 1997 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Board meeting, October 1997 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Board meeting, January 1998 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Board meeting, April 1998 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Board meeting, September 1998 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Conferences, miscellaneous, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Digital Future Coalition (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Mediagram, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Mediagram, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Mediagram, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Mediagram, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Motions book, 1976-1978 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - VEMA Clinch Region Conference, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - VEMA annual conference, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - VEMA leadership conference, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 15)
- Series XIII. 2003 Addition (Accession 40363), 1963-2002.
  - Annual conferences, 1983-1984 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Annual conference, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Annual conferences, 1987-1988 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Annual conference, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Annual conference, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 5-6)